Guide to the Pearl S.Buck Collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Pearl S.Buck Collection,
1932-1956.
Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.
.84 linear ft. (2 document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#0162
4079821
The collection consists primarily of carbon copies of manuscripts for Pearl S. Buck's short stories, essays, speeches, and screenplays. Some copies include corrections and additions in Buck's handwriting. The collection also includes publications by other authors including an exhaustive bibliography of Buck's work by Lucille S. Zinn of the Pearl S. Buck Birthplace Foundation, Inc.
Biographical Note
Pearl S. Buck is an American-born author and humanitarian best known for her fictional works containing nuanced descriptions of Chinese characters and lifestyles. Buck was a prolific writer credited with authoring more than 100 books of fiction and nonfiction. She was also known by her Chinese name, Sai Zhenzhu, and she published some works under the pseudonym John Sedges.
Born Pearl Comfort Sydenstricker in Hillsboro, West Virginia on June 26, 1892, Buck was the child of Presbyterian missionary parents who were primarily stationed in China. She was educated in Chinese villages until the age of 14 when she was sent to boarding school in Shanghai. She returned to the United States to study at Randolph-Macon Woman's College in Lynchburg, Virginia where she earned a bachelor's degree in 1914. She received a MA in English from Cornell University in 1926 as well as an honorary MA from Yale University later in life.
With the exception of the one year Buck spent at Cornell University, Buck lived, wrote and taught in China, primarily in Nanking, from 1918 to 1934 when she left China permanently for the United States. She attained international fame upon the publication of her second novel The Good Earth in 1931. The Good Earth won the Pulitzer Prize for the Novel in 1932. Buck's impressive body of work earned her the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1938. According to the Nobel Prize Committee for Literature, Buck earned the prize "for her rich and truly epic descriptions of peasant life in China and for her biographical masterpieces." She was the first American woman to win the Nobel Prize for Literature and continues to be the sole female recipient of both the Pulitzer Prize and the Nobel Prize to date.
Buck was also an influential humanitarian who campaigned on behalf of a wide variety of causes particularly those relating to international and interracial adoption. In 1949, Buck founded Welcome House, the first international, interracial, adoption agency in the United States. In 1964-65, Buck established Opportunity House, an organization designed to address the issues of poverty and discrimination faced by children in Asian countries. Buck died on March 6, 1973.
Scope and Content
The collection consists primarily of carbon copies of manuscripts for Pearl S. Buck's short stories, essays, speeches, and screenplays. Some copies include corrections and additions in Buck's handwriting. The collection also includes publications by other authors including an exhaustive bibliography of Buck's work by Lucille S. Zinn of the Pearl S. Buck Birthplace Foundation, Inc.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series.
Series I. Manuscripts by Pearl S. Buck, 1932-1956
Series II. Works by other authors, 1930, 1964, 1977
Subjects
Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973--Fiction; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973--Political and social views.; Sai, Zhenzhu, 1892-1973; Sedges, John, 1892-1973.; China--In literature.; China--Social life and customs--1901-1949.; American literature--20th century.; Authors, American--20th century.; Articles.; Bibliographies.; Carbon copies.; Drafts.; Essays.; Fiction.; Lectures.; Mimeograph copies.; Speeches.; Authors, American.; Novelists--20th century; Philanthropists.; Women authors, American.; Women dramatists, American.; Women novelists.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
06/30/92 M-92-06-30 Typescripts Asadorian, William Gift
Selected Related Material-- Other Repositories
The Papers of Pearl Buck 1933-1947, University of Virginia Libraries
Pearl S. Buck letters and papers, 1941-1969, Pennsylvania State University Libraries
- Series I: Manuscripts by Pearl S. Buck, 1932-1956
  This series is comprised of manuscripts for short stories, plays, essays, and speeches by Pearl S. Buck on a broad range of topics. Writings within the collection emphasize the need for global cross-cultural understanding in order to achieve harmony of the human race. The roles of various groups within the United States to achieve this goal are addressed in Buck's "A Letter to Colored Americans" essay and her speeches both to the New York Urban League and the New York Board of Education. Other items of note include the incomplete manuscript for Buck's biography of her father, Fighting Angel: Portrait of a Soul, which includes corrections and additions in Buck's handwriting, and the unpublished play script inserts and prose manuscript for Flight into China, which Buck later expanded into her novel Peony.
  - "Between These Two" undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Big Dance", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Big Wave 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    (Television drama from her book The Big Wave for the Alcoa Hour on NBC)
  - "The Bullfrog," undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Daughters of China", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Education for Life for Our World," Speech to Supervisors, Principals and First Assistants of the Board of Education, New York, January 19, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Empress: A Play in Three Acts, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Fiction and the Front Page", undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    (Published in Yale Review, March 1936)
  - "Fiction Versus Biography", undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Fighting Angel: Portrait of a Soul", undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Flight into China", undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Flight into China, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    (incomplete manuscript, unpublished, produced at the Paper Mill Playhouse in Millburn, New Jersey on September 11, 1939)
  - "Going Home", undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "The Good Deed", undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Heat Wave" 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    (published in American Mercury, April 1935)
  - "A Letter to Colored Americans", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "The Lovers", undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Letter Home", undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Of Men and Measuring Worms", undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "New Word for Children" undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Mrs. Witler’s Husband", undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Morning in Okinawa" undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The Old Chinese Nurse", 1932 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    (autobiographical essay published in Fortnightly, June 1932)
  - "Our Last Chance in China", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    (published in Common Sense, August 1944)
  - "The Patriot", undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Scene in the American Novel", undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The Sheriff", undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Speech Delivered at the Dinner of the New York Urban League, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "The Strawberry Vase", undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "The Three Daughters", undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "True Story U.S.A.", undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "The Wandering Little God", undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    (published in Asia, April 1928)
  - "What the Heart Must", 1937 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    (published in Woman's Home Companion, September 1937)
  - "What We Can Do About The Children Waiting", undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "The Writing of East Wind: West Wind", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    (published in Colophon, December 1932)
  - "Youth in China" undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series II: Manuscripts by other authors, 1930, 1964, 1977
  This series consists of published materials by other authors including an exhaustive bibliography of Buck's work by Lucille S. Zinn of the Pearl S. Buck Birthplace Foundation, Inc.
  - Cody, Lyman V, "An Introduction to Chinese Philosophy", undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Lindsey, Jason, "Pearl Buck I", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Slade, William Adams, China: A Bibliographical List, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Zinn, Lucille S., "The Works of Pearl S. Buck: A Bibliography", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)